<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>liamshort</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/</link><description>Recent content on liamshort</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:09:27 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://liamshort.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get MGN Replication Statistics</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/posts/mgn-replication-stats/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:09:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/posts/mgn-replication-stats/</guid><description>Overview There&amp;rsquo;s no easy way to retrieve the total volume of data replicated via MGN, so i wrote a wee script.
The below Python script fetches data on all source servers replicated to MGN, including disk sizes. It then parses the data and outputs to a CSV file in the local directory.
Users can define in the following parameters:
Parameter Description Default region The AWS Region eu-west-1 output Name of the CSV output file mgn_data exclude List of Source Server IDs to exclude [] max Maximum number of Source Servers to Parse 100 The script can be found here.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Actions and OICD with AWS</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/posts/github-oicd-aws/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 13:09:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/posts/github-oicd-aws/</guid><description>The Module This is a simple Terraform module to deploy an IAM Role which is assumable by GitHub Actions for a specific user or organisation. The module can be found here.
To consume the module, invoke as shown below:
module &amp;#34;github&amp;#34; { source = &amp;#34;github.com/liamshort/tf-mod-github-oidc-role&amp;#34; name_prefix = &amp;#34;MY_NAME_PREFIX&amp;#34; github_username = &amp;#34;MY_GITHUB_USERNAME&amp;#34; github_thumbprint = &amp;#34;6938fd4d98bab03faadb97b34396831e3780aea1&amp;#34; } Getting the Thumbprint The process for retrieving the Thumbprint can be found here.
Run:
openssl s_client -servername token.</description></item><item><title>AWS Toolkit Extension for VSCode</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/posts/aws-toolkit-vscode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:09:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/posts/aws-toolkit-vscode/</guid><description>Overview This website uses custom APIs hosted in AWS, built using API Gateway and backend Lambda Functions. To reduce the time taken for development and testing, I recently started using the AWS Toolkit extension for Visual Studio Code, which allows users to interact directly with the following services from their IDE:
API Gateway CloudFormation Cloudwatch Logs ECR ECS IoT Lambda S3 Step Functions Systems Manager Although it is possible to interact with these services via the AWS API, the extension does provide a nice UI.</description></item><item><title>GitHub CLI</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/posts/github-cli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 13:09:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/posts/github-cli/</guid><description>Overview I recently wanted to clone all my repositories from GitHub, easy right? Well, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a nice way around it. Apparently there&amp;rsquo;s no built in GitHub functionality for this. So, i tried to write my own Python script to clone all repos via the GitHub API. No Joy. I then stumbled upon the GitHub CLI.
Installation The GitHub CLI can be downloaded on a Mac or Linux machine with brew:</description></item><item><title>Random Profile Generator</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/posts/random-profile-generator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 13:09:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/posts/random-profile-generator/</guid><description>Overview The website thispersondoesnotexist.com is amazing, displaying a truly lifelike image of someone who does not exist. Developer by Nividia, this technology was intended for game design. The underlying code for the face generation can be found at SyleGen.
Upon seeing this website back in 2019, the first thing that came to my mind was a random profile generator. What if we could associate some realistic details with a completely non-existent person, making it very tricky to discern if the person actually exists.</description></item><item><title>Terraform and Git Repositories</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/posts/terraform-github-repositories/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 13:09:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/posts/terraform-github-repositories/</guid><description>Overview Just had a great idea for a new project and want to get coding ASAP? The first task is often setting up a Git repository to host the code. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and love to tinkerer, you can quickly accumulate repositories which makes things feel cluttered! Why not manage your repositories via Terraform?
Terraform, the open source Infrastructure as Code (IaC) tool developed by Hashicorp. Terraform uses Hashicorp Configuration Language (HCL) to define and deploy all manner of things and allows users to create and consume Providers, which are plugins for services like AWS, GCP, Azure, DigitalOcean.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://liamshort.dev/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/cv/</guid><description>About Highly motivated individual with a passion for cloud computing. Focused on the use of automation to solve technical challenges, and striving to create elegant, reliable, performant and cost-effective solutions as part of project deliverables. Enjoys collaborating closely with others in a team, or working individually to meet project goals.
Certifications Active Expired Technologies Experienced with the following technologies:
AWS Python Linux / Windows Bash / Powershell CICD Terraform Ansible CloudFormation GitHub / Git Employment History Cloudreach (2018 - Present) Senior Cloud Systems Developer Lead Thomson Reuters Elite (2015 - 2016) First Line Support Analyst Education Edinburgh Napier University (2013 - 2018) Computer Security and Forensics</description></item><item><title/><link>http://liamshort.dev/podcasts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/podcasts/</guid><description> podcasts episodes</description></item><item><title/><link>http://liamshort.dev/profiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/profiles/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>http://liamshort.dev/wordle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/wordle/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tags</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/tags/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/tags/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>