<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>aws on liamshort</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in aws on liamshort</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:09:27 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://liamshort.dev/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Get MGN Replication Statistics</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/posts/mgn-replication-stats/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 13:09:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/posts/mgn-replication-stats/</guid><description>Overview There&amp;rsquo;s no easy way to retrieve the total volume of data replicated via MGN, so i wrote a wee script.
The below Python script fetches data on all source servers replicated to MGN, including disk sizes. It then parses the data and outputs to a CSV file in the local directory.
Users can define in the following parameters:
Parameter Description Default region The AWS Region eu-west-1 output Name of the CSV output file mgn_data exclude List of Source Server IDs to exclude [] max Maximum number of Source Servers to Parse 100 The script can be found here.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Actions and OICD with AWS</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/posts/github-oicd-aws/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 13:09:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/posts/github-oicd-aws/</guid><description>The Module This is a simple Terraform module to deploy an IAM Role which is assumable by GitHub Actions for a specific user or organisation. The module can be found here.
To consume the module, invoke as shown below:
module &amp;#34;github&amp;#34; { source = &amp;#34;github.com/liamshort/tf-mod-github-oidc-role&amp;#34; name_prefix = &amp;#34;MY_NAME_PREFIX&amp;#34; github_username = &amp;#34;MY_GITHUB_USERNAME&amp;#34; github_thumbprint = &amp;#34;6938fd4d98bab03faadb97b34396831e3780aea1&amp;#34; } Getting the Thumbprint The process for retrieving the Thumbprint can be found here.
Run:
openssl s_client -servername token.</description></item><item><title>Random Profile Generator</title><link>http://liamshort.dev/posts/random-profile-generator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 13:09:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://liamshort.dev/posts/random-profile-generator/</guid><description>Overview The website thispersondoesnotexist.com is amazing, displaying a truly lifelike image of someone who does not exist. Developer by Nividia, this technology was intended for game design. The underlying code for the face generation can be found at SyleGen.
Upon seeing this website back in 2019, the first thing that came to my mind was a random profile generator. What if we could associate some realistic details with a completely non-existent person, making it very tricky to discern if the person actually exists.</description></item></channel></rss>